<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Adam L. Lyon</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a particle physicist and senior scientist at the Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fnal.gov&#34;&gt;Fermilab&lt;/a&gt;) in the Scientific Computing Division (&lt;a href=&#34;http://computing.fnal.gov&#34;&gt;SCD&lt;/a&gt;). I have several roles at Fermilab, including associate division head for science in the SCD, scientist on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://muon-g-2.fnal.gov&#34;&gt;Muon g-2 experiment&lt;/a&gt; and researcher in Quantum Computing in the Fermilab Quantum Institute (FQI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some history: I received my Ph.D. in particle physics in 1997 from the University of Maryland under Nick Hadley. For my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osti.gov/biblio/1421716&#34;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt;, I performed a search for hadronic supersymmetry (squarks and gluinos) at the D0 experiment at the Fermilab Tevatron particle collider. I did not find any supersymmetry, unfortunately (but neither has anyone else!). After graduating, I became a postdoc for the University of Rochester under Ed Thorndike stationed at Cornell University and worked on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CLEO_(particle_detector)&#34;&gt;CLEO experiment&lt;/a&gt;. There, I studied asymmetry in $b \rightarrow s\gamma$ decays (bottom quarks decaying to strange quarks and photons). In 2002, I returned to Fermilab and D0 as a scientist studying diboson events. D0 and the Tevatron ended operations in 2011 and soon thereafter I was one of the founding scientists on the Fermilab Muon g-2 experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy presenting science and computing to the public and students, having given several talks at libraries and schools.  I also give &lt;a href=&#34;https://ed.fnal.gov/programs/tours/dzero.shtml&#34;&gt;tours of the D0 detector&lt;/a&gt; as well as the Muon g-2 experiment. I once unknowingly gave a D0 tour to a New York Times journalist (he did not identify himself as such) that he described in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/28/travel/science-tourism-cern-fermilab.html&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; (see towards the bottom). The only celebrity I&amp;rsquo;ve given a D0 tour to is &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.fnal.gov/2017/02/hey-hey-its-monkey-micky-dolenz/&#34;&gt;Mickey Dolenz&lt;/a&gt; from the Monkees. Leading public tours is one of my favorite things to do and I&amp;rsquo;m amazed that people from all over the world specifically come to Fermilab as part of their vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find my short CV that I use for DOE proposals &lt;a href=&#34;files/lyon-doe-cv.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a list of recent &lt;a href=&#34;talks/&#34;&gt;Public Talks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;publications/&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
